Contact

+65-82357461 (Mobile) devanshjain@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/devansh-jain-6407b230 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Transportation Planning
Urban Planning
GIS

Languages

English

Hindi

Certifications

Policy Lessons from South Korea's Development

Fostering Growth and Inclusion in Asia's Cities

Public-Private Partnerships

Cities and Climate Change

Honors-Awards

Singapore Institute of Planners (SIP) Planning Awards

Future Ready Singapore Project: The Future of Mobility

Publications

Challenges and Improvements in Singapore's Urban Mobility

Urban heat Island and Change in Urban Microclimate: Causes, Impacts and Mitigation measures

Sustainable Transit Oriented Development, Solving congestion problem at Delhi

Urban Development and Environment, effective cross sectoral approach for green cities; A case example of Bhopal City

Bus Rapid Transit System: A milestone for Sustainable Transport:

Devansh Jain

URBANIST

Singapore

Summary

An Urbanist, with a robust enthusiasm for creating Spaces and Environments which are holistic, inclusive and augment the lives and livelihoods of the people living within. I look forward towards planning comprehensive and sustainable ecosystems in cities with complex built environments, to synthesize beneficial outcomes for its current and future citizens. My areas of expertise & interests include Urban Planning & Design, Sustainable Transportation Solutions, and Smart Cities.

Experience

Nanyang Technological University
Project Research Associate (Resilient and Inclusive Cities in Asia-Pacific)
August 2020 - Present (1 month)

Singapore

Surbana Jurong Private Limited

5 years 2 months

Executive Urban Planner April 2018 - August 2020 (2 years 5 months) Singapore

Responsible for Master Planning and land use development for Industrial, Urban, & Infrastructure Planning projects in Asia, Middle East and Africa markets. He is also part of the business development team assisting in collaborations with private and government sector clients to help secure projects and establish strong footprint for Surbana Jurong in the overseas markets.

Urban Planner

July 2015 - March 2018 (2 years 9 months)

Singapore

Assist the principal planner and project team for completion of project tasks and deliverables, by working on planning studies, gathering background a case study of Janmarg BRTS, Ahmadabad, India

information and data analysis, producing strategic and master planning related graphics and documents.

JTC Corporation
Urban Planner
May 2014 - July 2014 (3 months)
JTC Summit, Jurong East, Singapore

Assisted the lead planner for site analysis & development of strategies for one of the JTC's major industrial redevelopment project- Jurong Industrial Estate.

My Bus- Bhopal City Link Limited Transport Planner May 2013 - June 2013 (2 months)

Responsible to look after the introductory project execution for successful implementation of city's BRTS Bus operations, and effectively incorporating all of its components for the smooth operations of the India's longest BRTS Corridor.

Delhi Integrated Multi Modal Transit System Ltd. (DIMTS) Urban Planner May 2012 - June 2012 (2 months)

New Delhi, Delhi, India

Engaged for the preparation of Comprehensive Mobility Plans and Route Rationalization by developing sensible transportation strategies that encompassed the needs of all transport users including pedestrians and cyclists.

Mott MacDonald Urban Planner July 2011 - July 2011 (1 month) Noida Area, India

High Speed Rail:

• Pre-Feasibility Study for High Speed Rail Corridor (Delhi-Agra-Lucknow-Varanasi-Patna).

Delhi Metro Rail Corporation Ltd Transport Planner June 2011 - June 2011 (1 month) New Delhi, Delhi, India Involved in Route alignment and station area planning for Delhi Metro Phase 3, Central Secretariat- Kashmere Gate Corridor, a vital extension in Central & Old Delhi in India.

Town and Country Planning India Urban Planner May 2010 - June 2010 (2 months) Hoshangabad Area, India

Worked under Govt. of India for preparation, publication and implication of Eco Tourism Development Plan for planning of 524 km2 area located in central India.

Education

Lee Kuan Yew School of Public Policy

Executive Programme, Inclusive Citymaking (2018 - 2018)

National University of Singapore

Master of Urban Planning (2013 - 2015)

Maulana Azad National Institute of Technology
Bachelor of Planning, Urban Planning & Transportation · (2009 - 2013)

Jawaharlal Nehru School High School · (1997 - 2009)